http://www.triumph.co.uk/global-content/privacy-and-cookie-policy

Skip to main content
COOKIES
Triumph Motorcycles use cookies on this website to provide the best experience possible. If you continue you consent to this. You may choose to change your cookie settings. To find out more about the cookies we use and how to change your cookie settings please go to privacy & cookies.
Accept
TRIUMPH MOTORCYCLES Privacy Policy & Cookie Notice
We ask that you read this privacy notice carefully as it contains important information on who we are, how and why we collect, store, use and share personal information, your rights in relation to your personal information and on how to contact us and supervisory authorities in the event you have a complaint.
We may change this privacy notice from time to time. We will tell you when the notice was last updated, so you may take the time to read it if it has changed since your last visit. Privacy notice last updated: 11th May 2018
Who we are
Triumph Motorcycles Group Limited (Triumph Motorcycles Limited, Ashby Road, Measham, Swadlincote, Derbyshire, DE12 7JP) collects, uses and is responsible for certain personal information about you. When we do so we are regulated under the General Data Protection Regulation which applies across the European Union (including in the United Kingdom).
Information collected
We collect information about you when you use our online services, when you buy products or services from us and, in some cases, on paper (e.g. when you fill in a form at a dealer or when you visit one of our stands at a show). We collect the following information when you provide it to us: your name, address and contact details. We may also collect other personal information about you if it is relevant to the service you have requested (e.g. we might ask you for your age or about your driving licence if you are requesting a test ride).
Information collected from other sources
We also obtain personal information from other sources as follows:
Website usage information, collected through the use of cookies (see the cookie section below for more details).
Triumph Dealerships provide us with your contact details if you have asked to receive information or services from us, including purchase of a bike.
We may use public sources of data, for example, to support website functionality (e.g. to support authentication), and/or to maintain the accuracy of the information we hold. For example, we may check with the DVLA to ensure we have accurate owner information.
Please note: Personal data collected through the American website, TriumphMotorcycles.com, is collected and stored in the USA. If you complete a form or provide personal data in any other way on this part of our site, your data will be processed in accordance with privacy laws in the USA.
How we use your personal informationWe use your information in the following ways:
To provide you with the services you have requested.
To understand service and website use.
To help improve our services and products using your feedback.
If you have provided us with your consent, we will store your data and communicate Triumph marketing messages to you.
We may use your data to personalise your visit to our online services.
We may use your data to contact you about research.
We may ask you to complete a satisfaction survey when you buy a product or service from us.
When you purchase a motorcycle we may pass your details to a third party so additional services can be offered to you, such as extended warranties
and insurance offers (please see ‘who we share your personal information with’ below).
We may also publish articles with information collected about you. This will only happen where you have sent us the information yourself or you have
consented to its use.
On occasion we may send you invitations to complete research surveys.
Who we share your information with
We may share your information with the following third party suppliers selected by Triumph:
Those third parties who need to handle it so we can deliver the products you have ordered from us.
Marketing agencies to carry out marketing activities on our behalf.
Research agencies to carry out research on our behalf.
Data processors who we appoint to carry out work on our behalf.
Motorcycle service providers (such as insurers, warranty providers and roadside assistance companies) to provide you with the services you have purchased / requested.
Our authorised dealers and distributors (when booking a test ride or purchasing a bike for example)
Other companies or subsidiaries within the Triumph Motorcycles Group (including all companies under common control or ownership)
We may also use third party e-mail services to help us conduct market research. One of the companies used by us is Survey Gizmo, their privacy policy is available at http://www.surveygizmo.com/privacy/ (includes cookie information). The privacy policy covers Triumph as users of the system and you as someone responding to our surveys.
We endeavour to ensure all of our third party recipients are within the European Economic Area, however sometimes your personal data may by necessity be outside of the EEA – for further information including how we safeguard your personal data, see ‘Transfer of your information out of the EEA’.
We do not allow other companies to collect your personally identifiable data through our online services unless it is needed to provide a service you have requested.
We will share personal information with law enforcement or other authorities if required by applicable law.
We will not share or sell your personal data with any other third party.
Whether information has to be provided by you, and if so why
The provision of your name, address, delivery address is required from you to enable us to provide the goods you have purchased from us.
The provision of your phone number is required from you to enable us to ensure dealerships can provide any test rides you may have requested. The provision of driving licence details is required for the same purpose.
The provision of your email address is required from you where you have requested us to provide you with our e-newsletter and, in electronic format, product information or marketing information including promotional information.
How long your personal information will be kept
We will hold your name, address, contact details and VIN number(s) for the lifetime of the bike you have purchased, or until such time as you inform us of a change of ownership. We may also keep it to comply with our legal obligations, respond to queries and resolve any disputes, to meet our legitimate interests.
Your contact details used for marketing will be kept until you inform us that you no longer wish to receive such information from us, or until you have not interacted with Triumph for a period of 18 (eighteen) months.
Transfer of your information out of the EEA
Where Triumph Motorcycles shares personal information with a third party located outside the EEA, we conduct internal checks and use measures as approved by the European Commission to support adequate transfer of the information.
Internal checks identify if the country has been approved by the European Commission as having essentially equivalent data protection laws, or if there is a programme in place, such as the EU-US Privacy Shield programme, that the European Commission has approved as adequate. More information about the protections the European Commission has considered is available here
Your rights
Under the General Data Protection Regulation you have a number of important rights in connection with your personal information. These include the following: to withdraw consent where you have given it, to be informed and have access to your personal information, to be able to correct or complete inaccurate data, and in certain circumstances to restrict, request erasure, object to processing, or request portability of your personal information to another organisation.
Further information on each of these rights, including the circumstances in which they may apply, is available from the Data Protection Authority. [DPA Index]
If you would like to exercise any of those rights, then please write to:
Marketing Department,
Triumph Motorcycles Limited,
Normandy Way,
Hinckley,
Leicestershire.
LE10 3BZ.
United Kingdom
Let us have enough information to identify you, provide us with proof of your identity and address and let us know what information your request relates to.
If you would like to unsubscribe from any email newsletter, service emails or marketing you can also use the ‘unsubscribe’ option at the bottom of our email marketing communications to you. It can take up to 7 [seven] working days for this to take place, and if we are in the middle of a campaign you may still receive emails until it is completed.
Keeping your personal information secure
We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it, and require all the third parties we work with to have appropriate measures in place to maintain the security of your information.
We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected breach where we are legally required to do so.
If you would like detailed information on how to protect your information and your computers and devices against fraud, identity theft, viruses and many other online problems, please visit www.getsafeonline.org Get Safe Online is supported by HM Government and leading businesses.
How to complain
We hope that we can resolve any query or concern you raise about our use of your information.
The General Data Protection Regulation also gives you the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the European Union state where you work, normally live or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred. The supervisory authority in the UK is the Information Commissioner who may be contacted at https://ico.org.uk/concerns/ or telephone 0044 303 123 1113
Other websites
Our website and online services may contain links to other websites. This privacy policy applies only to official Triumph online services and events. When you visit other websites please make sure you read their privacy policy.
Please Note: This privacy policy does not cover the Triumph Motorcycles Repair and Maintenance Information (RMI) site, it has its own privacy policy.
Cookies and other tracking technology
Cookies
Cookies are small files which are stored on a user’s computer. They are designed to hold a modest amount of data specific to a particular client and website, and can be accessed either by the web server or the client computer. This allows the server to deliver a page tailored to a particular user, or the page itself can contain some script which is aware of the data in the cookie and so is able to carry information from one visit to the website (or related site) to the next.
Triumph will not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you. However, if you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by Triumph websites you can do this through your browser settings. The ‘Help’ function within your browser should tell you how.
Alternatively, you may wish to visit www.aboutcookies.org which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your machine as well as more general information about cookies.
Restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of our online services.
Please note that each online service that uses cookies should have its own cookie notice. Cookie lists:
• Triumph Motorcycles websites
http://www.triumphmotorcycles.co.uk/global-content/website-cookies-used
• For The Ride Blog
http://fortheride.com/privacy-cookie-policy/
Pixel Tags
We may use pixel tags as part of our online services. Pixel Tags (also called clear GIFs, web beacons, or pixels) are small blocks of code on a webpage that can collect information such as:
The IP (Internet Protocol) address of the device that accessed the page containing the tag
The URL (Uniform Resource Locator) of the page on which the pixel tag appears
The time the page containing the pixel tag was viewed
The type of browser that fetched the pixel tag, and
The identification number of any cookie on the computer previously placed by that server.
E-mail tracking
When corresponding with you via HTML capable e-mail, we may use 'format sensing' technology, which allows pixel tags to let us know whether you received and opened our e-mail.
We may use unique hyperlinks in e-mails we send to you; this is to see if e-mails have been opened and responded to.
Do not Track (browser setting)
Our online services do not currently recognise ‘do not track’ signals.
